Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/mantus (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

DWBI Techinical Manager/Solution Architect/Data Modeler

Bobj, Cognos & MicroStrategy OLAP ETL (Informatica, SAP Data Service, ODI)

Languages

Hindi, Bengali

Certifications

Google Cloud Certified -Professional Machine Learning Engineer

Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Engineer Associate

Advanced Clinical Data Science

AWS Certified Machine Learning – Specialty

IBM Certified Solution Expert - Cognos BI

Mantu Samadder

Lead Director - Enterprise Data and Machine Learning Dallas-Fort Worth Metroplex

Summary

Mantu Samadder is a Data Modernization and Analytics Solution (AWS, Azure, GCP and Snowflake) Leader in Deloitte Consulting. Mantu Samadder is an expert in implementing innovative / reusable solutions that helped in reducing operating cost and improving performance. Mantu is an expert in crafting technical solutions for complex business problems and analytics use cases, created multiple strategic roadmaps, many assets, accelerators, point of views, playbooks, best practices for the firm. Mantu is also AWS, GCP and Azure Certified AI & Machine Learning Architect.

He has more than two decades (22 years) of IT consulting experience mainly focus on:

- => Data Modernization Solution Delivery,
- => Data, Analytics and Integration Solutions Architecture,
- => Enterprise Domain and Reference Architecture,
- => Data Modeling, Data Profiling and Data Cleansing,
- => Data Governance and Master Data Management,
- => Clinical Data Science and Al Solution Architecture,
- => Designing & Managing multiple data modernization solutions for Healthplan & Provider, MedTech, Financial and Retail services industries using wide varieties of Modernized Cloud (AWS, Azure, GCP and Snowflake), Big Data and Traditional Technology platform

Mantu has implemented multiple Health & Clinical Innovation, Value Base Care, Care Advance Analytics, Referral Management Solutions, 360 degree Patient View, Cancer Institute Analytics, Provider Spend Analytics, Financial Intelligence, Credit Risk Intelligence, Customer Profitability Analysis, Customer Data Hub Solutions over several years.

Mantu has a very strong interpersonal, strategic leadership, functional and technical skill, to drive any data modernization, digital transformation, cloud data analytics solution design and

implementation initiatives being at customer front, to execute at its perfection, meeting the client and organization goals and objectives.

Experience

CVS Health

Lead Director - Enterprise Data and Machine Learning August 2022 - Present (9 months)

Irving, Texas, United States

Leading Cloud Data Modernization and Solution Engineering initiatives in GCP.

Deloitte Consulting
Data Modernization and Analytics Solution Leader
April 2017 - August 2022 (5 years 5 months)
Dallas, Texas, United States

Mantu Samadder 's Core Competencies are Leading Consulting & Delivery for Modernization Solutions, Strategizing Enterprise Data Analytics & Integration Solution Architecture, Clinical Data Science and Al Solution Architecture, Enterprise Domain and Reference Architecture, Enterprise Service Integration (API), Enterprise Data Governance and Master Data Management, Data Visualization, Self Service Business Intelligence, Dimensional/OLAP Modeling, BI OLAP & Analytics Design, Canonical/UML/XML Modeling, Enterprise Data Warehouse, Enterprise Data Lake Design, Designing & Managing multiple data modernization solutions for Healthplan & Provider, MedTech, Financial and Retail services industries using wide varieties of Modernized Cloud (AWS, Azure, GCP and Snowflake), Big Data and Traditional Technology platform

Cognizant Technology Solutions 6 years 4 months

Associate Director - Projects / Principal Data Architect May 2014 - April 2017 (3 years)

Newark, New Jersey

Architecting, Modeling, Designing and Managing multiple DW (BI & ETL) Projects

Senior Architect / Senior Manager - Projects January 2011 - May 2014 (3 years 5 months) Woolland Hills, CA

Managing multiple DW & BI Projects

Wipro Technologies Solution Architect / Technical Project Manager February 2010 - January 2011 (1 year)

Worked on multiple Enterprise Business Intelligence (EBI) projects for Retail Domain using Bobj (BO, WI, Deski and Xcelsius) all range of products and Informatica.

I have a very strong project management, interpersonal, strategic leadership, functional and technical skill, to drive any BI & DW initiatives/programs/projects being at customer front, to execute at it perfection, meeting the client and organization goals and objectives. I want to be an excellent BI & DW practice solution expert for DSS Implementation Unit.

Tech Mahindra

Technical Project Manager April 2006 - February 2010 (3 years 11 months)

I have leaded and managed end to end multiple BI/DWH projects using different OLAP & Modeling tools like Cognos Suite of Products, Business Objects Range of Products and Erwin on Oracle & DB2 databases

It was really a great experience to be in such a role.

Knowledge Dynamics

Senior Consultant / Technical Lead August 2004 - March 2006 (1 year 8 months)

I leaded many BI Cognos and Business Objects projects mainly for banking and finance domain. This is one of best BI/DWH consulting company based in Singapore I had worked for....

Tata Consultancy Services
Senior Systems Engineer
March 2001 - July 2004 (3 years 5 months)

I started my career with Tatainfotech Ltd in the year 2001, which had been acquired by TCS. I learnt many things,. I leaded multiple projects for Telecom, Insurance and banking industries, with major contribution in data modeling and BusinessObjects technology, design & development and implementation using oracle database.

Education

The Johns Hopkins University Master of Science - MS, Artificial Intelligence · (2021 - 2024)

Harvard Business Publishing

Certificate of Global Business Leadership, Economics; Leadership; International Studies; Marketing; Finance; Operations and Strategy Management · (2008 - 2008)

Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay
Master of Technology, Chemical Engineering · (2001)

Jadavpur University
Bachelor of Engineering, Chemical Engineering · (July 1999)